# **Jay Liu**

# Full-Stack Web Developer

San Juan, Puerto Rico | (86) 170-8206-2602 | soon.nerd@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/jay-liu-dev p-mob2015.github.io

## **Professional Experience**

## React Native Developer (part-time)

Feb 2019 - Apr 2019

## Sigsense Technologies

- Re-hired by the old client to deliver the mobile user experience.
- Designed mobile UI/UX based on the existing web UI/UX.
- Defined the re-usability scope of the React Web code-base.
- Built a device monitoring dashboard for iPhone and Android using React-native.
- Integrated Segment SDK, Push notifications and Amplitude SDK.

## React / Ruby on Rails Engineer

Oct 2018 - Feb 2019

## MyTime

- Contributed to the migration of AngularJS 1.X code-base to React.
- Developed merchant data ingestion UI.
- Troubleshot i18n issues both on the front-end and the back-end.

## React / Ruby on Rails Developer

May 2018 - Sep 2018

## Linux Academy

- Helped the company quickly launch the new enterprise version in ReactJS.
- Refactored old front-end code-base for the better scalability.
- Took part in the design/implementation process of the REST API in Ruby on Rails.
- Handled complicated styling issues with Material UI components.

## Ruby on Rails / React Engineer

Feb 2018 - Aug 2018

## Simple.Space

- Worked on different Ruby on Rails gems for user activities tracking.
- Utilized worker architecture using Sidekiq.
- Took advantage of React-on-rails for the partial rendering of React components within Rails views
- Made use of HAML as the template engine.
- Successfully combined micro-services and Rails views in a single project.
- Written specs and ensured 85%+ test coverage for all Ruby on Rails modules and classes.
- Put design patterns and TDD into practice.

## React / GraphQL Developer

Feb 2018 - Jun 2018

#### **Acuity Scheduling**

- Wrote solid React code/architecture for a new SaaS branch of Acuity Scheduling.
- Integrated a React application with the GraphQL database using Apollo.
- Collaborated with the designer and back-end developer and suggested a few points that were accepted and implemented for improved user experience.
- Implemented highly complex render components and HOCs.
- Documented the custom React components using Storybook.

## **Summary**

**Passion-driven** software architect with 9 years of field experience.

Liu is a software architect with comprehensive knowledge and experience in Web application development. His mantra of Quality over Quantity always brings about premier online products. He is an early adapter of the cutting edge coding practices, frameworks, and the technologies. He communicates early and often while keeping up the great teamwork.

## **Skills**

Javascript

9 years of experience

Ruby on Rails

6 years of experience

ReactJS

6 years of experience

NodeJS

6 years of experience

VueJS

4 years of experience

Angular

4 years of experience

**EmberJS** 

5 years of experience

## React / React Native / Node Developer

## Jan 2018 - Apr 2018

## Certifications

## Strive for College

- Developed mobile counter-part for Strive-For-College application.
- Integrated Twilio and developed solid messaging architecture.
- Utilized Twilio and Parse SDK for 80% of the back-end integration.
- Built state management system using Redux.
- Took part in the design process of the micro-services using NodeJS.
- Created mobile UI/UX using React-native-elements and Styled-components.

## **Business Writing**

**Network Plus** 

**Associate** 

ExpertRating Inc.

**UML2 Professional** Object

**Oracle Database SQL Certified** 

CompTIA

Oracle

Management Group

**Business English Certificate Higher** 

University of Cambridge

## NodeJS Developer

DigiPro, Inc.

- Supported the mobile application development with REST API using Node.js and Express.js.
- Migrated a substantial MS SQL database to MySQL.
- Developed solid authentication and access control model using Passport.js.
- Set up Microsoft Azure deployment utilizing Docker containers.

## React / Ruby on Rails Engineer

Jul 2016 - Oct 2017

Nov 2017 - Apr 2018

Airnest (Measure.com)

- Developed flight track player that resembles Youtube video player, but with a lot of metrics and meters.
- Developed flight area selection tool using Mapbox, available both in 2D and 3D.
- Developed parser module for drone flight log files in Ruby on Rails.
- Styled the whole UI/UX to be mobile-responsive.

## Ruby on Rails Developer

Feb 2017 - May 2017

#### Robot Riot

(Online 3D fishing game engine)

- Transformed old fishing tournament system to a more engaging one.
- Took care of refactoring, test coverage and the error-proof migration of the DB.
- Played a pivotal role in defining the technical specifications.
- Suggested and exercised TDD for the development of the game engine.
- Identified edge cases in gameplay and implemented the best solutions.
- Established a solid flow of unit testing on large sets of data.
- Reduced beta test failures by 85%.
- Increased monthly revenue by 25% (the fiscal year 2017).

## Lead Developer

Sep 2015 - Feb 2017

## Sigsense Technologies

- Built the whole REST API using NodeJS and ExpressJS.
- Built the whole front-end using ReactJS and Redux.
- Implemented 9 different types of data visualizations using D3 and Highcharts.
- Envisioned and built Machine learning UI that analyzes the patterns in device incidents.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering, A

2001 - 2006

Tsinghua University

## **Testimonials**

Liu, I'm working on some of your flow code right now, and I just felt the need to say thanks! It's good code. Easy to work with, reusable. After working with some other people's code for a while and having to rewrite it because it didn't make sense it's a please to read through some of yours.

~ Brian Jenkins, AcuityScheduling

It was an absolute pleasure working with Liu - rare to find such a skilled developer who exceed expectations on both communication and delivery of tasks with a good alignment and understanding of business requirements. We were continuously on the same page when it came to deliverables. There's no doubt we will continue to work with Liu on upcoming projects and feature-sets.

~ Raf Gouel, Simple.Space

I worked with Liu on a React Native project over the course of 14 weeks. Not only was Liu proficient in building the logic of the application, but he was able to match exactly the UI/UX of the existing web application. I can see that Liu has a deep, formal understanding of software development. He employed thoughtful techniques and was very thorough on the project.

~ Sebastian Stant, StriveForCollege

# Extra-professional experience

Co-Founder 2011 - Present

SMD SG

Inspired by the increasing local demands of mechanical parts and engineering resources by the horizontal mechanical industry, I, with two of my friends from college, started a broker service. The idea is simple, we classify the availability and technical specs of different mechanical parts. We strive to collect as much information as possible from as many providers as possible. This is our main business operation.

We provide the needy with tailored information and often act as a retailer of some popular merchandises. Recently, we have introduced a service that accelerates the process of short-term contracts for engineering aid and on-site training.

Volunteer 2017 - Present

Friends of Nature

Part-Time Lecturer in Programming Languages 2010 - 2011

Teach For Malaysia